[Back to Gift Store >

×](https://www.unrefugees.org/gifts)

United States Association for UNHCR Privacy Policy
--------------------------------------------------

Last Updated: July 18, 2023

The United States Association for UNHCR (USA for UNHCR) strives to protect the privacy and security of the personal information we collect, use, share, and otherwise process as part of our operations. We also believe in transparency and are committed to informing our supporters about how we treat the data we collect and process, including the types of information we collect and how we may use or share that information.

This Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy") describes our practices regarding your personal information when you make a donation, use our website, [www.unrefugees.org](http://www.unrefugees.org/) (the "Website"), or otherwise interact with us for our services or solutions. The Website is intended for users located in the United States and is not intended for users located in other countries, including the European Union and European Economic Area. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand how we treat your personal information. By using the Website or otherwise providing any information to us, you consent to this Privacy Policy.

**Information We May Collect**

We may collect the following information from you for the purposes described in the "How We May Use Your Information" and "How We May Share or Disclose Your Information" sections of this Privacy Policy.

**Contact Information:** When you make a donation, request updates from our website, sign a petition, assist with fundraising, or otherwise interact with us, we may collect your name, email address, mailing address, and/or mobile telephone number. You consent to and will receive emails from us at the email address provided. SMS alerts are available on most carriers. Message frequency varies. Message & Data Rates may apply.

By providing your mobile telephone number, you are opting in to receive text messages regarding USA for UNHCR's events, updates, fundraising or donating opportunities, and other promotional messages. You are not required to provide your mobile telephone number to make a donation or purchase products and services with USA for UNHCR. SMS alerts are available on most carriers. Message frequency varies. Message & Data Rates may apply. For general text message updates from USA for UNHCR, text PROTECT to 75871. If you wish to unsubscribe from text messages at any time, simply text message STOP to 75871. Text HELP to 75871 with any questions or concerns. You can re-subscribe at any time by texting PROTECT to 75871.

**Donation Information:** When you make a donation, we may also collect information that is required to process the transaction or provide you with a tax receipt, including the amount of your donation. We use a third-party payment processor and do not process or store any credit card information provided by you in connection with a donation.

**Communications, Feedback, Support, and Inquiries:** If you contact us, we may receive your name and email address, as well as the subject matter of your message and any comments, ratings, reviews, content, or responses that you choose to provide. When you communicate with us, we may retain your communications.

**Social Media Information:** If you connect with us through a third-party social network or other websites, we may collect information such as your name, username, email address, and other profile information in connection with your social medial account.

**Usage Data:** When you use the Website, we may collect information from your browser or device, which includes the date and time of your access, your location, your Internet Protocol (IP) or unique device identifier, your device type, your operating system, and information about what pages you visit.

**Cookies and Similar Technologies:** This Website may use cookies and similar technologies described in the "Cookies and Similar Technologies" section of this Policy.

We may also receive information about you from third parties in order to improve our services to you, provide you with information or updates you have requested, advise you of activities that we believe may interest you, and for other purposes.

**How We May Use Your Information**

We may use the information we collect and derive for the following purposes:

* Process and complete donations and other transactions;
* Operate and improve our services and the website;
* Manage our relationships with our supporters and donors;
* Ensure the privacy and security of our website and services;
* Communicate with you and respond to your feedback, requests, or questions;
* Promote campaigns or opportunities that we believe may interest you;
* Assess the success of our fundraising campaigns;
* To administer a contest, promotion, campaign, or survey;
* Determine and track user interests, trends, needs, and preferences;
* Comply with federal, state, or local laws and regulatory obligations;
* Accomplish any other purpose related to any of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy for which your information was provided to us;
* Exercise or defend legal rights or claims;
* Create, use, retain, or disclose de-identified or aggregated data;
* Any other purpose with your consent.

**How We May Share or Disclose Your Information**

USA for UNHCR does not sell or rent your information to third parties nor do we send mailings on behalf of other organizations. We may share your information in the following contexts:

**Corporate Affiliates:** We may share your information with our corporate subsidiaries and affiliates.

**Acquisitions and Similar Transactions:** We may disclose your information in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of our assets.

**Legal Obligations:** We may disclose information as required by law, in response to subpoenas, warrants, court orders, or other legal process, or if we reasonably believe such action is necessary to comply with applicable laws and the reasonable requests of regulators, law enforcement, or other public authorities or quasi-government authorities, including fraud detection agencies. We may also share information to establish or exercise our legal rights or claims; to defend against a legal claim; and to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities, suspected fraud, or safety of person or property.

**Service Providers:** We may share information with our service providers to provide operational or other support services on our behalf. Among other things, service providers help us administer the Website, process donations and other transactions; send marketing and other communications to you; and assist with other legitimate purposes permitted by law. We limit the information shared with these parties to that which is reasonably necessary to perform their functions.

**Select Non-Profit Organizations:** From time to time, we may exchange names, email addresses and mailing addresses with select non-profit organizations to reduce fundraising costs and improve communications. You may request that your information not be shared with these organizations at any time by contacting our Donor Care team at (800) 770-1100.

**Professional Advisors:** We may share your information with our insurers and other professional advisors, including attorneys and accountants, that need access to your information to provide operational or other support services on our behalf.

**With Your Consent or at Your Direction:** We may ask, from time to time, if you would like us to share your information with other unaffiliated third-parties who are not described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy. We may disclose your information in this context with your permission or upon your direction.

**Deidentified or Aggregated Data:** We may disclose aggregated or de-identified information that does not identify any specific individual, such as groupings of demographic data or preferences.

**How We Protect Your Information**

We recognize the importance of safeguarding your information and endeavor to maintain reasonable and appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures to help keep your information secure and from being accidentally lost, used, altered, disclosed, or accessed in an unauthorized manner.

While our security measures seek to protect any personal information in our possession, no security system is perfect, and no data transmission is 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to or from the website.

**Links to Third Party Websites**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any third-party websites or applications. Our website contains links to other third-party sites. These links are to external resources and third parties that have their own privacy policies. If you follow any links that direct you away from the Website, including links to social media sites or to other websites, this Privacy Policy will not apply to your activity on the other sites you visit. USA for UNHCR cannot and does not (1) guarantee the adequacy of the privacy and security practices employed by or the content and media provided by any third parties or their websites; (2) control third parties' independent collection or use of your information; or (3) endorse any third-party information, products, services, or websites that may be reached through embedded links on the Website.

Any information provided by you or automatically collected from you by a third party will be governed by that party's privacy policy and terms of use. USA for UNHCR is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. If you are unsure whether a website is controlled, affiliated, or managed by us, you should review the privacy policy and practices applicable to each linked website.

**Opt-Out Policy and Your Rights and Choices Regarding Personal Information**

**Email Opt-Out:** If you no longer wish to receive communications from us via email, you may opt-out by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of our emails or by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.unrefugees.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and providing your name and email address so that we may identify you in the opt-out process. Once we receive your instruction, we will promptly take corrective action.

**Text Messaging Opt-Out:** If you wish to unsubscribe from text messages at any time, simply text message STOP to 75871. You can re-subscribe at any time by texting PROTECT to 75871.

**Accuracy and Updating Your Information:** Our goal is to keep your information accurate, current, and complete. If any of the information you have provided to us changes, please let us know via the "Contact Us" details at the end of this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for any losses arising from any inaccurate, deficient, or incomplete personal data you provide to us.

**European Union and California Data Privacy Rights**

USA for UNHCR adheres to ensuring the security and protection of the information we possess. Our approach to data protection aligns with relevant data protection laws and regulations. While these terms explain how we collect and use your information, if you are an individual in a European Union nation or a California resident, you may request information about our use of your personal information, request to restrict use of your personal information, or request that your personal information be erased from USA for UNHCR. To make such a request, please send an email to: [\[email protected\]](https://www.unrefugees.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Cookies and Similar Technologies**

A cookie is a small file created by a web server that can be stored on your device (if you allow) for use either during a particular browsing session (a "session" cookie) or a future browsing session (a "persistent" cookie). Session cookies are temporarily stored on your device and remain there until they expire at the end of your browsing session. Persistent cookies remain stored on your device until they expire or are deleted by you. First-party cookies are set by the website you are visiting and they can only be read by that website. Third-party cookies are set by a party other than that website. You can block and control cookies using the information noted below. Our website uses cookies and similar technologies to improve functionality, to measure and track how you interact with the Website, to perform analytics, to market to you, to track ad-driven activity, and to otherwise tailor our communications with you.

In addition to cookies, there are other automatic data collection technologies, such as Internet tags, web beacons (clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs), and navigational data collection (log files, server logs, etc.) that can be used to collect data as users navigate through and interact with a website. From time to time, we may use Google Analytics for the purposes of analyzing aggregate statistical data about website usage. Display Advertising features also place an additional cookie, or small text file, on your browser, containing an anonymous identifier. This allows Google to provide aggregate reports on the demographics and interests of website visitors and customize advertising on the Internet based on your browsing activity. We do not control these third-parties' technologies or how they may use your data once you are referred to these third-party websites. If you have any questions, you should contact the responsible party directly or consult their privacy policies.

Most web browsers are set by default to accept cookies. You may opt out of any of these services by clearing the cookies from your browser; disabling cookies entirely; opting out of  [Google interest-based ads](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en&SF_monthly=7011K0000022TYDQA2&SF_onetime=7011K0000022TXzQAM); and/or clicking [here](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/&SF_monthly=7011K0000022TYDQA2&SF_onetime=7011K0000022TXzQAM) to opt-out page to opt out of targeted ads from participating advertising networks including Facebook.

**Children's Online Privacy Protection Act**

Our website and services are not directed to children aged 13 or younger, nor is information knowingly collected from children under the age of 13. No one under the age of 13 may access, browse, or use the Website or provide any information to or on the Website. If you are under 13, please do not use or provide any information on the Website (including, for example, your name, telephone number, or email address). If we learn that we have collected or received personal information from a child under the age of 13 without a parent's or legal guardian's consent, we will take steps to stop collecting that information and delete it. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under the age of 13, please contact us via the "Contact Us" details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy.

**Updates and Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may modify, change, or update this Privacy Policy to reflect any changes to how we treat your information or in response to changes in law. Should this Privacy Policy change, we will post all changes to this Privacy Policy on this page. Any such changes, updates, or modifications will be effective immediately upon posting. The date on which this Privacy Policy was last modified is identified at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

You are expected to, and you acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to, carefully review this Policy prior to using the Website, and from time to time, so that you are aware of any changes. Your continued use of the Website after the "Last Updated" date will constitute your acceptance of and agreement to such changes and to our collection and sharing of your information according to the terms of the then-current Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Policy and our practices, you should not use the Website.

**Contact us:**

This website is owned by the United States Association for UNHCR. Please feel free to contact us in any of the following ways if you have questions or concerns.

Mail: United States Association for UNHCR 1310 L Street NW, Suite 450 Washington, DC 20005

Phone: (800) 770-1100

Fax: (202) 296-1081

Email: [\[email protected\]](https://www.unrefugees.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**EU/EEA/UK Addendum**

This Addendum of the Privacy Policy (the "Addendum") applies only if you use our Website, make a donation, or otherwise use our services from a country that is a Member State of the European Union or European Economic Area (collectively, "EU"), the United Kingdom ("UK"), or Switzerland, and it supplements the information in the remainder of our Privacy Policy, above.

The term "Personal Data" as used in this Addendum shall mean any information that relates to an identified or identifiable living individual.

**Legal Basis for Data Processing**

We may process your Personal Data in connection with any of the purposes and uses set out in this Privacy Policy based on one or more of the following legal grounds:

**Performance of a Contract:** As necessary to perform the services you have requested or to comply with your instructions or other contractual obligations between you and us.

**Legal Obligations:** As necessary to comply with our legal obligations as well as to keep records of our compliance processes (for example, to comply with applicable accounting rules and to make mandatory disclosures to law enforcement).

**Legitimate Interest:** Because of our legitimate interests, or those of a third-party recipient of your Personal Data, to make the processing necessary, provided those interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. As set forth below, you have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data on the basis of our legitimate interests and we must stop such processing unless we have a compelling interest in the continued processing that overrides yours.

**Vital Interest:** As necessary to protect your vital interests.

**Public Interest:** As necessary in the public interest.

**Consent:** Because you have expressly given us your consent to process your Personal Data in a particular manner.

**EU and UK Data Subject Rights**

If you are located in the EEA, the UK, Switzerland, you have the following rights under the General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR"). All requests should be sent to the address noted in the "Contact Us" section of this Privacy Policy, and we will fulfill requests to the extent required by applicable law.

**Right of Access.** To the extent required by law, you have the right to receive confirmation as to whether or not Personal Data concerning you are being processed, and, where that is the case, access to the Personal Data and the following information: the purposes of the processing; the categories of Personal Data concerned; and the recipients or categories of recipient to whom the Personal Data have been or will be disclosed. We will provide a copy of your Personal Data in compliance with applicable law.

**Right of Rectification.** Our goal is to keep your Personal Data accurate, current, and complete. Please contact us if you believe your information is not accurate or if it changes.

**Right to Erasure.** In some cases, you have a legal right to request that we delete your Personal Data when (1) it is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected, (2) consent has been withdrawn in certain instances, (3) you have objected to the processing in certain instances, (4) the Personal Data has been unlawfully processed, (5) the Personal Data have to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation; and (6) the Personal Data were collected in relation to the offer of information society services. However, the right is not absolute. When we delete Personal Data, it will be removed from our active servers and databases, but it may remain in our archives when it is not practical or possible to delete it. We may also retain your Personal Data as needed to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, or enforce any agreements.

**Right to Restrict Processing.** You have the right to restrict the processing of your Personal Data when (1) the accuracy of the Personal Data is contested, for a period enabling the controller to verify the accuracy of the Personal Data; (2) the processing is unlawful and you oppose erasure and request a restriction instead; (3) we no longer need the Personal Data, but you need us to keep it for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims; or (4) you have objected to us processing the Personal Data, pending resolution of the objection.

**Right to Portability:** You have the right to request that we make available, in a portable form, your Personal Data in our possession so that you can transfer to a third party.

**Right to Object.** In certain circumstances, you have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data where the processing is necessary for performance of a task carried out in the public interest, for our Legitimate Interests, or for the Legitimate Interests of others. You also have the right to object where Personal Data is processed for direct marketing purposes or for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes.

**Right to Withdraw Consent.** If you have provided your consent to the collection, processing, and transfer of your Personal Data, you may have the right to fully or partially withdraw your consent. Once we have received notice that you have withdrawn your consent, in whole or in part, we will no longer process your information for the purpose(s) to which you originally consented and have since withdrawn unless there are compelling legitimate grounds for further processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims. Withdrawal of consent to receive marketing communications will not affect the processing of Personal Data for the provision of our Services.

**Data Retention**

Please review the "Data Retention" section in the Privacy Policy above.

The Basics

About Us

Contact Us

Stay Connected

1310 L ST NW, STE 450, Washington, DC 20005 1-(855)-808-6427 EIN 52-1662800 [Privacy Policy](https://www.unrefugees.org/privacy-policy/) ©2024 USA for UNHCR

SPOTLIGHT: This World Refugee Day, meet Lucky, a brave Rohingya refugee making an incredible impact! [**READ →**](https://www.unrefugees.org/news/usa-for-unhcr-selects-former-rohingya-refugee-lucky-karim-as-world-refugee-day-featured-storyteller?utm_medium=web&utm_source=homepage&utm_campaign=US_PS_EN_WRD2024___240613&utm_content=banner&SF_onetime=701Rf00000FUHXSIA5&SF_monthly=701Rf00000FUDQeIAP "Meet Lucky")
